Japan is one of the most
unreached areas in the world.
Less than 1% of the population are
Christians, and less than 1% of the 1%
are Seventh-day Adventists.
Until 2025, Tokyo was the largest urban
area in the entire world.
Nearly one-third of the
population lives in this area.
Yet, Tokyo remains largely unreached.
Mission Unusual Tokyo was launched with a
bold vision to initiate a
disciple-making movement,
house church planting movement, a small
groups community
multiplying all over the place.
That was the vision, to establish 30
congregations and hundreds and hundreds
of small groups all over Tokyo.
Not simply adding membership or not
simply building church buildings,
not addition, but the goal of Mission
Unusual Tokyo was
multiplication of disciples.
Over the past six years, the project has
been a profound journey of faith in one
of the world's most challenging cities.
When we formed our initial director team
of five deeply dedicated families, three
from abroad and two from Japan,
we knew the evangelistic potential of MUT
was immense and precisely because of that
greater potential, we
faced spiritual warfare.
I believe the enemy saw what MUT could
achieve and actively tried, crushing.
Despite everyone's earnest prayers and
incredibly hard work, the team Dynamics
faced heart-breaking struggles.
Ultimately, the team had to disband and
three of our precious missionary families
have since left Japan.
But we know that in Christ, after death,
come a resurrection, we truly believe MUT
experienced a kind of death, only to be
resurrected by God's grace.
The tears and hard work of those families
who left were absolutely not in pain.
The local people, they so faithfully
trained, remain with us today.
The seeds they planted have taken root.
Through two cycles of ACT's church
planting residency program,
34 church members were
trained to do church planting.
As of 2026, we have about 10 house church
groups in Tokyo area.
We do not yet have 30
churches or 300 small groups,
but something deeper began to take place.
The DNA of church planting,
disciple-making culture is
slowly being established.
Japanese leaders are stepping up.
Young people are opening up their homes
and dedicating their lives to advance the
gospel work forward.
Although we do not have any official
church in the traditional sense,
we have small groups of believers and
seekers gathering together in their homes
for Bible study, prayer,
and fellowship every week.
These 10 small groups or house church
groups together form
one network of churches
that support each other,
host trainings together,
and share responsibilities to manage
various other church functions
such as tithe,
offering, and board meetings.
I urge a new development professionals to
kickball with both focuses and all the
branches of the church work of ours to
scheme for the city.
In 202 feet, Japan Union Conference
selected six pastors to study the online
church planting certificate course by
Foherer Theological Seminary.
Japan Union Conference is serious about
advancing the mission of church planting
in Tokyo and beyond.
To advance the church planting work in
Japan, training of both church members
and pastors is essential.
We are deeply grateful to the General
Conference for supporting the MUT
project, both
spiritually and financially.
Because of this generous support, we have
learned valuable lessons, built strong
foundations, and seen encouraging growth.
Now, based on what we have gained during
these five years, we are ready to move
forward with a clear vision.
We believe God has been leading us, and
we look forward to expanding this
ministry across the nation for His glory.
We sincerely appreciate your continued
prayers and partnership as we
take this next step together.
Friends have told me that church
buildings feel too
formal and intimidating.
Some say the community already seems
closed, or that only
holy people can attend.
Others feel church sermons are too
difficult and worry they would not
understand or might even fall asleep.
Through house church, I
discovered something powerful.
When gatherings are held in a home or any
familiar space, people
feel more comfortable.
My friends are willing to come because
they know and trust me.
Whether in a home, cafe, office, or
rental space, the key is simple.
A trusted friend is there.
That makes it easier to come.
This is one of the unique strengths of
house church ministry.
House churches also allow flexibility.
We can shape each gathering to welcome
non-Christians and
connect with those who attend.
Through house churches, I want to
introduce my best friend,
Jesus Christ, to my friends.
I hope to see more house churches across
Japan so that more people can meet Him.
For that to happen, we need more
Adventist families
willing to open their homes.
Please pray for Japan that God will bless
and multiply Adventist
homes in Tokyo and beyond.
We need more Adventist families willing
toえる present topic.
We need more Adventism Finition than in Japan.
Church planting efforts not only take
place in homes, but
also in businesses as well.
私は職場で金曜日の夜のベスパーを企画しリードしています。
私の上司とその旦那さんは3年前にバプテスマを受けました。
Church planting cannot be done alone.
Adventist homes, opening up homes for
house church activities is one way to do.
But there's other ways, other creative
ways to do church planting as well.
From 2023 to 2025, three young Adventist
nurses, Haruna, Kotomi, and Minami,
decided to live together in a shared
apartment community called Mamezon to
expand the kingdom of God.
Three women, one shared
home, one shared mission.
They opened their doors to co-workers,
friends, and seekers.
They shared healthy meals.
They sang praise songs.
They created a place where people could
belong before they believed.
They did not always begin with deep
theology, but they were connected to God.
And through them, others
slowly began connecting to Him.
One of those seekers
was a young man named Aoi.
He was not a Christian.
He began attending the small house church
gatherings in their apartment.
He studied.
He listened.
He experienced community.
He believed Aoi was baptized.
And on January 25,
2026, they were married.
From shared home to house church to
baptism to marriage.
May God bless their new chapter of life.
The financial sacrifice, time, and
dedication of the three young ladies of
Mamezon has inspired many
across Tokyo and beyond.
Hearing house church stories of Mamezon,
an older couple in Kobe also
decided to open up their homes
to invite young people for fellowship,
prayer, and delicious homemade meals.
Sometimes, my friends stay at my place
for days, weeks, or even months.
And as we share life together, the
conversation naturally
flows to Jesus Christ.
I hope and I pray that sometime, someday,
they will meet Jesus.
Last year, Harui and
another friend were baptized.
I continue to pray and hope that one day,
all my other friends will meet Jesus
Christ and accept Him
as their Lord and Savior.
I come from a non-Christian background.
In all late night conversations about
God's grace and life's difficult
questions, my heart began to change.
Here is what we have learned.
To have multiplying explosive number of
house churches, we need
explosive number of Adventist homes.
Homes that open doors.
Homes that welcome seekers.
And homes that become mission centers.
Mission Unusual Tokyo continues.
And by God's grace, this
project has only just begun.
God has now blessed us
with the new director team.
And those trained members have stepped up
as the faithful
church planting volunteers.
Because of this resurrected effort,
New group are forming and precious souls
are continually being baptized.
Thank you for your unwaiving support.
Your resources and your
prayer through the storms.
We give all the glory to God as this
incredible mission
continues to move forward.
Thank you.